Guide to the Time Inc. Time Publishing and Business Records 1929-1999 MS 3009-RG 24
New-York Historical Society
- Series IV. Promotion and Public Affairs Department Records, 1955-1999; 155.1 Linear feet in 156 record cartons, 1 document case, and 2 flat boxes
  - Subseries IV.J. Event Files, 1962-1990; 32 Linear feet in 33 record cartons
    - Presentations/Symposiums/Talks: Association of National Advertisers: Rockwell, Willard Speech, 1970 (Offsite-box 3113, Folder 31)
    - Presentations/Symposiums/Talks: Foreign Policy Association Tour, 1967-1968 (Offsite-box 3114, Folder 1-4)
    - Presentations/Symposiums/Talks: Panel Discussion by James Akins, James Bill, Richard Helms, Walter Levy, Dimitri Simes, Joe Sisco, and Dale Tahtinen, with Time Magazine: Transcript, 1979 (Offsite-box 3258, Folder 8)
    - Presentations/Symposiums/Talks: Presentation of Thomas Jefferson Cover to University of Virginia, 1976-1977 (Offsite-box 3114, Folder 5)
    - Presentations/Symposiums/Talks: Road Show: "Time, Gentlemen, Please", 1972 (Offsite-box 3114, Folder 6)
    - Presentations/Symposiums/Talks: Time Inc. Western Symposium: Transcripts, 1982 (Offsite-box 3258, Folder 9-10)
      Time Inc. hosted a symposium with panels titled "The Risk Merchants of Silicon Valley," "Computers and Information," "The New Immigrants," and "Terrorism." Panelists included James Treybig of Tandem Computers, Steve Jobs of Apple Computer, and Utah Governor Scott Matheson. Guests included California Governor Edmund "Jerry" Brown.
    - Presentations/Symposiums/Talks: Trade Symposium, 1971 (Offsite-box 3114, Folder 7-8)
  - Subseries IV.K. Newstour Files, 1963-1996; 50.1 Linear feet in 48 record cartons, 1 document case, and 2 flat boxes
    According to a history written up by Time Inc. in 1990 when considering reviving the newstour program, newstours were created by Time magazine in 1963 to give a small group of thirty to fifty American leaders the opportunity to visit areas of the world in the news and meet with local leaders. The newstours were arranged by Time Inc., funded by the participants, and encouraged by the U.S. government, though they played no role in the tours.
    Participants were invited because of their expressed interest in world affairs and because they were known to be citizens seeking opportunities to contribute to global stability and world peace. The primary purpose was inquiry rather than commercial or economic information. Participants were heads of their fields in industry, education, community affairs, and other professions; each paid their own expenses and relied on the Time publisher's office and public affairs department with assistance from local Time news bureaus to arrange the program and meetings with international leaders in politics and culture. Newstour participants notably met with: John F. Kennedy, Richard Nixon, Nikolai Khrushchev, Ferdinand Marcos, and Eisaku Sato.
    Time also sponsored a 1973 visit for Japanese business executives to Detroit and a 1970 trip to Tehran for an economics conference. "Update on America" and "Report on America" were opportunities for foreign business executives to travel to the United States and meet with Time journalists, American business leaders, and government representatives. Newstours that traveled the United States were sometimes called "reverse newstours."
    For a history and background of newstours, please refer to "Newstour 1990" files in Books and Binders.
    More files from the 1995 newstours are in the Corporate Public Affairs record group. Corporate Public Affairs may have taken over the responsibilities for this event in later years.
    Newstour Files contain records created by Time Public Affairs during the planning and realization of newstour trips. Papers and Books and Binders were not found together although both groups seem collated by Public Affairs or from Public Affairs files. The majority of photographic material documenting the newstours was separated by Time Public Affairs, and is in the series Public Affairs: Photographs and Negatives.
    Records on the planning of the TIME Newstour '95 are in Donald Barr files in MS 3009-RG 5. Records on the planning of the CHINA 1999 newstour are in Special Events Manager Jean C. Gussenhoven Files in this record group.
    Organized into two subsubseries:
    Subsubseries III.K.1. Administrative Files
    Subsubseries III.K.2. Books and Binders
    - Subsubseries IV.K.1. Administrative Files, 1963-1996; 25.1 Linear feet in 25 record cartons and 1 document case
      The files planning and overseeing newstours for Time look like someone (either Time Public Affairs or the Time Inc. Archives) collected all the newstours files from everyone in Time Public Affairs and grouped them together by newstour. People represented include Public Affairs directors Robert Sweeney and Robert Ankerson, associate director Stan Kapner, special events managers Irina Bagration, Rita Robinson, and Nini Gussenhoven, and Public Affairs and Promotion staff Elizabeth Jones, Jim Roy, Anne Rhoades, Nancy Hall Megan, Patricia Donham Hodges. Early newstour files have records from Time publisher Bernie Auer, assistant publisher Lawrence Laybourne, Sweeney as an assistant to the publisher, business manager Kelso Sutton, assistant business manager John Keller, and Robinson as Laybourne's executive assistant.
      Records include itineraries and agenda; lists of and biographies on participants; collected information on the tour locations; cable correspondence; correspondence with participants, staff on location, foreign governments, companies, and other representatives; correspondence with accommodations and transportation providers; interoffice correspondence; travel brochures and guides; information on memento gifts sent to participants; hotel information; invoices and bills; memoranda to file; programs and menus for events at visited locations; business cards; and branded stationary, stickers, and luggage tags. Some materials from earlier newstours are in later newstour files, probably for reference or research purposes during planning. Rebilling files includes bills sent by Time Inc. to participants for their share of the tour costs and frequently include notes of appreciation from the participants.
      The General files contain materials related to several different newstours and a binder on the history of the newstours, and may have been collected at a later date for reference in planning a new newstour.
      Organized chronologically by newstour.
      - General: General, 1971-1989 (Offsite-box 2860, Folder 1-2)
      - General: History and Background, 1996 (Offsite-box 2860, Folder 3)
      - General: Invitations, 1964-1983 (Offsite-box 2860, Folder 4)
      - General: Programs: 1963-1987 (Offsite-box 2860, Folder 5-6)
      - General: Rebilling, 1983-1989 (Offsite-box 2860, Folder 7)
      - Time Newstour of Europe, 1963 (Offsite-box 2860, Folder 8-9)
      - Time Newstour of Southeast Asia, 1965 (Offsite-box 2860, Folder 10-14)
        Locations visited for the Southeast Asia newstour included Bangkok, Thailand; Hong Kong; New Delhi, India; Taipei, Taiwan; Singapore; Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia; and Tokyo, Japan with an additional stop in Honolulu, Hawaii.
      - Time Newstour of Southeast Asia, 1965 (Offsite-box 2861, Folder 1-15)
      - [Time Newstour of Southeast Asia]: Charles Percy Film, [1965] (Offsite-box 4146, Item 3)
        1 audiotape reel: analog; 12 1/2 in., 1/4 in. tape. On container label: "Charles Percy film - 'Time Life Tour of Asia'."
      - Time Newstour of Africa (canceled), 1966 (Offsite-box 2861, Folder 16-18)
      - Time Life International General Information, 1963-1967 (Offsite-box 2861, Folder 19-20)
        While the folder label says "TLI General Information," records include significant material on the 1967 Indonesian Investment Conference along with other newstours. Indonesian Investment Conference attendees were invited to the newstour participants reunion in 1968 tacitly defining this event as a newstour although it is called a conference.
      - Time Newstour of Eastern Europe, 1966-1967 (Offsite-box 3012, Folder 11-22)
        Locations visited during the Eastern Europe newstour were all capital cities including Belgrade, Serbia (part of Yugoslavia at the time); Bucharest, Romania; Budapest, Hungaray; Moscow, Russia; Prague, Czech Republic (Czechoslovakia at the time); Vienna, Austria; and Warsaw, Poland.
      - Time Newstour of Eastern Europe, 1966-1967 (Offsite-box 3046)
      - Time Newstour of Eastern Europe, 1966-1967 (Offsite-box 3047)
        The Planning folder in this box includes a transcript of a talk given by editor-in-chief Hedley Donovan about the newstour.
      - Time Newstour of Eastern Europe, 1966-1967 (Offsite-box 3048, Folder 1-7)
      - U.S. Newstour (canceled), 1965-1969 (Offsite-box 3048, Folder 8-19)
        This newstour of the United States was originally proposed for Japanese businessmen, then for international businessmen, then restricted to European businessmen. It was ultimately canceled due to lack of acceptances to participate and conflict with the annual meeting of the Industrial Conference Board. It is possible that ideas from this tour were reconstituted in the 1971 Report on America (which had many of the same locations) and the Time Survey 1973: Japan/USA.
      - U.S. Newstour (canceled), 1965-1969 (Offsite-box 3082, Folder 1-28)
      - Time Newstour of the Far East, 1968-1969 (Offsite-box 2861, Folder 21-24)
        The locations visited during the Far East newstour included Bangkok, Thailand; Jakarta, Indonesia; Kyoto, Osaka and Tokyo in Japan; Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia; Manila, Philippines; Ho Chi Minh City (at the time Saigon), Viet Nam; Seoul, South Korea; and Singapore with a stop in Honolulu, Hawaii.
      - Time Newstour of the Far East, 1968-1969 (Offsite-box 2862)
      - Time Newstour of the Far East, 1968-1969 (Offsite-box 2863)
      - Time Newstour of the Far East, 1968-1969 (Offsite-box 2864, Folder 1)
      - China Newstour (unrealized), 1971 (Offsite-box 2864, Folder 2)
      - 1971 Report on America (Offsite-box 2864, Folder 3-28)
        Locations visited during the 1971 newstour of the United States include the Kennedy Space Center in Florida (Cape Kennedy at the time); Dartmouth College in Hanover, New Hampshire; Westchester and Manhattan, New York including Gracie Mansion; and Washington, D.C.
      - 1971 Report on America (Offsite-box 2865)
        Box 2865 includes transcripts from speeches in New York by Andrew Heiskell, Henry Ford II, Veron E. Jordan, Jr., John V. Lindsay, Patrick Murphy, and Hugh Sidey.
        The folder on Gifts includes digital material:
        1 magnetic card (IBM). On sleeve label: "Card No. 855. Covering Note with pictures __ Europeans."
        The folder on Summary Book and Mailings also includes digital material:
        1 magnetic card (IBM).
      - 1971 Report on America (Offsite-box 3082, Folder 29-38)
      - 1971 Report on America (Offsite-box 3083, Folder 1-61)
      - Time Survey 1973: Japan/USA (Offsite-box 3083, Folder 62-68)
        Locations visited for the the 1973 newstour of the United States include Stanford University in California; Phoenix, Arizona; the NASA Space Center in Houston, Texas; Ford Motor Company in Detroit, Michigan; Washington, D.C.; and New York, New York.
      - Time Survey 1973: Japan/USA (Offsite-box 3084, Folder 1-20)
      - Time Mid East Newstour, 1975 (Offsite-box 2866)
        Locations visited during the Middle East newstour include Algeria; Jordan; Lebanon; Syria; Egypt; Israel; Jerusalem; Kuwait; Lebanon; Saudi Arabia; Turkey; and Iran.
      - Time Mid East Newstour, 1975 (Offsite-box 2867, Folder 1-5)
      - European Agency Week, 1977 (Offsite-box 3114, Folder 9-20)
        For this reverse newstour, fifty-five advertising agency executives from Europe traveled to New York as guests of Time's international editions. They met with staff from all departments at the Time offices and attended panel sessions with the International Advertising Association. Records include itineraries, bills, photographs of the event, and records on Robert Sweeney's initial tripvisit to Europe.
      - Time/Update on America '77, 1977 (Offsite-box 3084, Folder 21-31)
        Locations visited for the 1977 newstour of the United States include Washington, D.C. and New York, New York. The program focused on briefings from the Supreme Court, the Pentagon, the Federal Reserve, the State Department, the Central Intelligence Agency, and the United Nations.
      - Time/Update on America '77, 1977 (Offsite-box 3085)
      - Time/Update on America '77, 1977 (Offsite-box 3086, Folder 1-8)
      - Time/Update on America '77, 1977 (Offsite-box 3259, Folder 8-41)
      - Time/Update on America '77 [RESTRICTED], 1977 (Offsite-box R56)
      - Time/Update on America? '77 or '85: Photographs, 1977 or 1985 (Offsite-box 3086, Folder 9)
        These photographs were found among folders from both newstours and are not specifically identified. They may be from neither newstour.
      - Time Newstour of Africa/Mid East, 1978 (Offsite-box 2867, Folder 6-45)
        Locations visited during the Africa/Middle East newstour include Amman, Jordan; Cairo, Egypt; Cape Town and Johannesburg in South Africa; Dakar, Senegal; Arusha and Dar es Salaam in Tanzania; Jerusalem; and Riyadh, Saudi Arabia.
      - Time Newstour '81: Middle East, Eastern Europe, and Soviet Union, 1978-1981 (Offsite-box 2867, Folder 46-59)
        Locations visited during the Middle East, Eastern Europe, and Soviet Union newstour include Belgrade, Serbia (part of Yugoslavia at the time); Budapest, Hungaray; Gdansk and Warsaw in Poland; Kuwait; Moscow, Russia; Oman; and Riyadh, Saudi Arabia.
      - Time Newstour '81: Middle East, Eastern Europe, and Soviet Union, 1978-1981 (Offsite-box 2869)
        The folder Mailings to Guests includes digital material:
        1 magnetic card (IBM). On card sleeve: "Dr. Kasofsky's post-Newstour followup letter. 11/5/81."
        2 magnetic cards (IBM). On card sleeve: "Sweeney 1st Time."
        2 magnetic cards (IBM). On card sleeve: "Sweeney Alumni."
        1 magnetic card (IBM). On card sleeve: "Med. Dept. return envelope."
        1 magnetic card (IBM). On card sleeve: "Letter #3."
        3 magnetic cards (IBM). On card sleeve: "Meyers Letter."
      - Time Newstour '81: Middle East, Eastern Europe, and Soviet Union, 1978-1981 (Offsite-box 2867)
      - Time Newstour '81: Middle East, Eastern Europe, and Soviet Union, 1978-1981 (Offsite-box 2867, Folder 1-2)
      - Time/Update on America '81, 1981 (Offsite-box 2870)
      - Time/Update on America '81, 1981 (Offsite-box 2871, Folder 3-26)
      - Time Newstour '83: Mexico, 1983 (Offsite-box 2871, Folder 27-40)
        Locations visited in the 1983 newstour include El Paso, Texas; Monterrey, Mexico; and Panama City, Panama.
      - Time Newstour '83: Mexico, 1983 (Offsite-box 2872, Folder 1-39)
        The folder titled Originals includes digital material:
        1 computer disc (floppy disk): 5 1/4 in.
      - Time/Canada Update on America '85, 1985 (Offsite-box 3086, Folder 10-39)
        Locations visited for this 1985 newstour of the United States were completely within Washington, D.C. Participants were executives from Canada.
      - Time/Canada Update on America '85, 1985 (Offsite-box 3087)
      - Time Newstour '85: Pacific Rim, 1985 (Offsite-box 2872, Folder 40-58)
        Locations visited during the Pacific Rim newstour include Beijing, Canton and Shanghai in China; Hanoi, Viet Nam; South Korea; and Manila, Philippines.
      - Time Newstour '85: Pacific Rim, 1985 (Offsite-box 2873, Folder 1-27)
      - Time Newstour '85: Pacific Rim [RESTRICTED], 1985 (Offsite-box R56)
      - Time Newstour '87: Soviet Union (USSR), 1987 (Offsite-box 2873, Folder 28-34)
      - Time Newstour '87: Soviet Union (USSR), 1987 (Offsite-box 2874, Folder 1-22)
      - Time Newstour '87: Soviet Union (USSR) [RESTRICTED], 1987 (Offsite-box R56)
      - Time Newstour: Communism, 1990 (Offsite-box 2874, Folder 23)
      - Time Newstour: Mexico, Central America, South America, 1991 (Offsite-box 2874, Folder 24)
    - Subsubseries IV.K.2. Books and Binders, 1963-1995; 25 Linear feet in 26 record cartons, 2 flat boxes
      Books and Binders contain the published and branded binders and books containing background and participant information for each newstour. Information includes background on locations and cultures visited, biographical and historical information on the location hosts and companies, news clippings on current events at each location, itineraries, participants' biographical information, souvenir photograph books, maps, speech transcripts, and participants' gift lists. While some of these binders may be labeled as belonging to an individual, it looks like Public Affairs reclaimed the binders for reference purposes. Oversized binder covers were separated from their materials and rehoused in separate boxes for preservation purposes.
      Books and Binders are arranged chronologically by newstour. Oversized covers removed from the books and binders are housed in boxes 2822 to 2830 and 3260.
      - Time Newstour of Europe, 1963 (Offsite-box 2812, Folder 1-5)
      - Time Newstour of Europe, 1963 (Offsite-box 3258, Folder 11)
      - Time Newstour of Europe: Published Photograph Albums, 1963 (Offsite-box 3246)
      - Time Newstour of Europe (binder cover), 1963 (Offsite-box 2822, Folder 8)
      - Time Newstour of Southeast Asia, 1965 (Offsite-box 2812, Folder 6-11)
      - Time Newstour of Southeast Asia, 1965 (Offsite-box 3089, Folder 1)
      - Time Newstour of Eastern Europe, 1966 (Offsite-box 2812, Folder 12-14)
      - Time Newstour of Eastern Europe (binder cover), 1966 (Offsite-box 2828, Folder 1)
      - Indonesian Investment Conference, 1967 (Offsite-box 2812, Folder 15)
      - Time Newstour of the Far East, 1969 (Offsite-box 2813, Folder 1-8)
      - Time Newstour of the Far East, 1969 (Offsite-box 3258, Folder 12)
      - Time Newstour of the Far East (binder cover), 1969 (Offsite-box 2822, Folder 3-7)
      - Time Newstour of the Far East (binder cover), 1969 (Offsite-box 3260)
      - Time Newstour of the Far East (binder cover), 1969 (Offsite-box 2828, Folder 2)
      - Iran Investment Conference, 1970 (Offsite-box 2813, Folder 9-10)
      - Iran Investment Conference (binder cover), 1970 (Offsite-box 2822, Folder 4)
      - 1971 Report on America (Offsite-box 2813, Folder 11)
      - 1971 Report on America (Offsite-box 2814, Folder 1)
      - 1971 Report on America (Offsite-box 3088, Folder 1-5)
      - Time Survey 1973: Japan/USA (Offsite-box 2814, Folder 2-4)
      - Time Survey 1973: Japan/USA (binder cover) (Offsite-box 2822, Folder 1)
      - Time Mid East Newstour, 1975 (Offsite-box 2814, Folder 5-12)
      - Time Mid East Newstour, 1975 (Offsite-box 3089, Folder 2-3)
      - Time Mid East Newstour, 1975 (Offsite-box 3088, Folder 6)
      - Time Mid East Newstour, 1975 (Offsite-box 3258, Folder 13)
      - Time Mid East Newstour (binder cover), 1975 (Offsite-box 2823, Folder 2-3)
      - Time/Update on America '77, 1977 (Offsite-box 2815, Folder 1-5)
      - Time/Update on America '77 (binder cover), 1977 (Offsite-box 2823, Folder 1)
      - Time/Update on America '77 [RESTRICTED], 1977 (Offsite-box R28)
      - Time Newstour of Africa/Mid East, 1978 (Offsite-box 2815, Folder 6-14)
      - Time Newstour of Africa/Mid East, 1978 (Offsite-box 2816, Folder 1-15)
      - Time Newstour of Africa/Mid East, 1978 (Offsite-box 2817, Folder 1-5)
      - Time Newstour of Africa/Mid East, 1978 (Offsite-box 3088, Folder 7)
      - Time Newstour of Africa/Mid East (binder cover), 1978 (Offsite-box 2823, Folder 4-7)
      - Time Newstour of Africa/Mid East (binder cover), 1978 (Offsite-box 2824, Folder 1-3)
      - Time Newstour of Africa/Mid East (binder cover), 1978 (Offsite-box 2825, Folder 4-6)
      - Time Newstour of Africa/Mid East (binder cover), 1978 (Offsite-box 2828, Folder 3)
      - Time Newstour '81: Middle East, Eastern Europe, and Soviet Union, 1981 (Offsite-box 2817, Folder 6-18)
      - Time Newstour '81: Middle East, Eastern Europe, and Soviet Union, 1981 (Offsite-box 2818, Folder 1-12)
      - Time Newstour '81: Middle East, Eastern Europe, and Soviet Union, 1981 (Offsite-box 3088, Folder 8)
      - Time Newstour '81: Middle East, Eastern Europe, and Soviet Union, 1981 (Offsite-box 3089, Folder 4)
      - Time Newstour '81: Middle East, Eastern Europe, and Soviet Union, 1981 (Offsite-box 3258, Folder 14-18)
      - Time Newstour '81: Middle East, Eastern Europe, and Soviet Union, 1981 (Offsite-box 3259, Folder 1-2)
      - Time Newstour '81: Middle East, Eastern Europe, and Soviet Union (binder cover), 1981 (Offsite-box 2825, Folder 1-3)
      - Time Newstour '81: Middle East, Eastern Europe, and Soviet Union (binder cover), 1981 (Offsite-box 2826, Folder 1-2)
      - Time Newstour '81: Middle East, Eastern Europe, and Soviet Union (binder cover), 1981 (Offsite-box 2827, Folder 5-6)
      - Time Newstour '81: Middle East, Eastern Europe, and Soviet Union (binder cover), 1981 (Offsite-box 2829, Folder 1-3)
      - Time Newstour '81: Middle East, Eastern Europe, and Soviet Union (binder cover), 1981 (Offsite-box 3260)
      - Time/Update on America '81, 1981 (Offsite-box 2818, Folder 13-15)
      - Time/Update on America '81 (binder cover), 1981 (Offsite-box 2827, Folder 4)
      - Time Newstour '83: Mexico, 1983 (Offsite-box 2818, Folder 16-17)
      - Time Newstour '83: Mexico, 1983 (Offsite-box 2819, Folder 1-15)
      - Time Newstour '83: Mexico, 1983 (Offsite-box 2820, Folder 1-3)
      - Time Newstour '83: Mexico, 1983 (Offsite-box 3088, Folder 9)
      - Time Newstour '83: Mexico, 1983 (Offsite-box 3259, Folder 3-4)
      - Time Newstour '83: Mexico (binder cover), 1983 (Offsite-box 2826, Folder 3)
      - Time Newstour '83: Mexico (binder cover), 1983 (Offsite-box 2827, Folder 1-3)
      - Time Newstour '83: Mexico (binder cover), 1983 (Offsite-box 2830, Folder 2)
      - Time Newstour '85: Pacific Rim, 1985 (Offsite-box 2820, Folder 4-10)
      - Time Newstour '85: Pacific Rim, 1985 (Offsite-box 3088, Folder 10)
      - Time Newstour '85: Pacific Rim, 1985 (Offsite-box 3259, Folder 5-7)
      - Time Newstour '85: Pacific Rim: Photobook, 1985 (Offsite-box 3040, Folder 2)
      - Time Newstour '85: Pacific Rim (binder cover) - UPDATE, 1985 (Offsite-box 2830, Folder 3)
      - Time Newstour '85: Pacific Rim (binder cover), 1985 (Offsite-box 3260)
      - Time Newstour '85: Pacific Rim [RESTRICTED], 1985 (Offsite-box R28)
      - 1985 Update on America (Offsite-box 2820, Folder 11-14)
      - 1985 Update on America (binder cover) (Offsite-box 2830, Folder 4-6)
      - Time Newstour '87: USSR, 1987 (Offsite-box 2821, Folder 1-2)
      - Time Newstour: Communism, 1990 (Offsite-box 2821, Folder 3-4)
      - Time Newstour '95: Cuba, 1995 (Offsite-box 2821, Folder 5-10)
  - Subseries IV.L. Photographs and Negatives, 1972-1987; 8 Linear feet in 9 record cartons
    Photographs and Negatives contain photographic material requested and collected by Time Public Affairs. The materials document events thrown by Time Inc. or Time magazine such as office parties, corporate gatherings, presentations or appearances by Time staff, art exhibitions, and newstours; or attended by Time staff such as annual expositions and political conventions.
    Records include primarily negatives, contacts sheets, and photographs produced by Time Inc. photographer Tony Ruta. The majority of photographic material is black-and-white. Additional materials include Photographic Laboratory order forms, slides, sticky notes, newstour itineraries, and a very small amount of correspondence.